American Federation of Labor Records, Part 2 on Microfilm 5760 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Labor Records, Part 2 on Microfilm
1936-1953
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
5760 mf
4.22 cubic feet
38 microfilm reels
Microfilm, records (documents).
Documents in extensive detail the emergence of the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) in the 1930s and subsequent competition and cooperation between the CIO and American Federation of Labor (AFL) through the close of that decade, until the early 1950s.
3337585
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 21, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, June 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The American Federation of Labor (AFL) was the first federation of labor unions in the United States. It was founded in May of 1886 in Columbus, Ohio. Samuel Gompers of the Cigar Makers' International Union was elected president every year except one up until he passed away in 1924. The AFL was the largest union grouping in the United States in the first half of the 20th Century, even after the Congress of Industrial Organizations (CIO) was formed.
In 1955 the AFL merged with the CIO (longtime rival), to form the AFL-CIO, a federation of unions which remains today.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises the following subseries: historical file (1934-1942); convention file (1935-1952); relations with the CIO (1935-1950); political collaboration with the CIO (1937-1947); papers favoring AFL-CIO unity (1935-1951); national and international union correspondence (1935-1951); State Federations of Labor correspondence (1935-1945); central labor union correspondence (1935-1950); local union correspondence (1937-1947); and miscellaneous correspondence (1936-1950).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5478: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records 5478 mf: AFL-CIO Railway Employees' Department Records on Microfilm 5366: American Federation of Labor, Railway Employees Department vs. Union Pacific Railroad Company, Hanson et al. Records 5402 mf: Correspondence of American Federation of Labor President William Green on Microfilm 5431 mf: Letterpress Copybooks of Samuel Gompers and William Green, Presidents on Microfilm 5757 mf: American Federation of Labor Records, Part 1: Strikes and Agreement File on Microfilm 5761 mf: William Green Papers on Microfilm 5360: Buck's Stove and Range Company vs. American Federation of Labor Court Records
Labor leaders; Labor unions, United States, Officials and employees; American Federation of Labor; Boehm, Randolph; Green, William, 1872-1952; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.)
3337585
- Historical File, 1934-1942. (Reel 1)
  - 0001. Box 1a/Folder 1. Correspondence 200 pages., 1934-1935; 1 (Reel 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Major Subjects: San Francisco 1934 Convention, San Francisco 1934 Executive Council Meeting, Resolutions, Industrial Unionism, Wagner Act, Union Organization (Auto Workers, Aluminum Workers), Questionnaires, Statistics, Atlantic City 1935 Convention, Atlantic City 1935 Executive Council Meeting, Minutes of Meetings, Committee for Industrial Organizations. Principal Correspondents: C.J. Weaver, Harry C. Louden, Ernest Claxton, Al Cook, Henry S. Bierre, Earl Cast, A.O. Wharton, J.W. Pickering, F.J. Dillon, Carl J. Shipley, H.H. Richardson, George F. Addes, James J. Hailey, Charlton Ogburn, John T. Flynn, Homer Martin, John L. Lewis, Sidney Hillman, David Dubinsky, Thomas McMahon, Thomas H. Brown, Max Zaritsky, Harvey C. Fremming, Charles P. Howard.
  - 0201. Box 1a/Folder 2. Correspondence. January-June. 213 pages., 1936; 2 (Reel 1)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Metal Workers, Committee for Industrial Organization), Miami 1936 Executive Council Meeting, Industrial Unionism, Washington 1936 Executive Council Meeting, Dual Unionism, Resolutions, News Releases, Minutes of Meetings. Principal Correspondents: John Brophy, H.W. Morgan, John L. Lewis, Sidney Hillman, David Dubinsky, Thomas F. McMahon, Harvey C. Fremming, Max Zaritsky, Thomas H. Brown, James Starr, Frank Morrison, Charles P. Howard, D.W. Tracy, Kathryn Lewis, John Fitzpatrick, M.F. Tighe, Thomas Kennedy, J.L. Coulter, Woodruff Randolph, Joseph Schlossberg, Michael F. Greene, John M. Sherwood, Thomas H. Brown, George M. Harrison, Marx Lewis, Matthew Woll, Joseph N. Weber, Harry C. Bates, T.A. Rickert, Frank Duffy, Felix H. Knight, William L. Hutcheson, G.M. Bugniazet, Joseph G. Klein.
  - 0414. Box 1a/Folder 3. Correspondence. July. 255 pages., 1936; 3 (Reel 1)
    Major Subjects: Committee for Industrial Organization, Union Organization (Metal Workers), Industrial Unionism, Washington 1936 Executive Council Meeting, News Releases, Dual Unionism, Minutes of Meetings, Petitions and Protests regarding Suspension of Charters. Principal Correspondents: Charles P. Howard, Thomas McMahon, Sidney Hillman, Edward Flore, W.D. Mahon, Max Pincus, Edward Lamb, Max Zaritsky, Charlton Ogburn, John L. Lewis, E.N. Nockles, David Dubinsky, George M. Harrison, G.M. Bugniazet, H.A. Bradley, H.D. Fremming, Max B. Klein, John P. Frey, Glen W. McCabe, M.F. Tighe, Homer Martin, Thomas H. Brown, Sherman Dalrymple, A.O. Wharton, Frank Morrison, J.J. Handley, Matthew Woll.
  - 0669. Box 1a/Folder 4. Correspondence. August 1-14. 213 pages., 1936; 4 (Reel 1)
    Major Subjects: Washington 1936 Executive Council Meeting, Minutes of Meetings, Suspension of Charters, News Releases, Petitions and Protests regarding Suspension of Charters, Industrial Unionism, Resolutions, Committee for Industrial Organizations. Principal Correspondents: John P. Frey, David Dubinsky, John L. Lewis, Sidney Hillman, Thomas F. McMahon, H.C. Fremming, Thomas H. Brown, Glen McCabe, M.F. Tighe, Sherman Dalrymple, Homer Martin, Michael F. Greene, Charles P. Howard, John A. O'Connell, John M. Sherwood, Ivan F. Cox.
  - 0882. Box 1b/Folder 1. Correspondence. August 15-31. 173 pages., 1936; 5 (Reel 1)
    Major Subjects: Petitions and Protests regarding Suspensions, Resolutions, Committee for Industrial Organizations, Union Organization (Metal Workers), Industrial Unionism. Principal Correspondents: Charles P. Howard, John L. Lewis, John Brophy, Thomas G. Gillis, Edward W. Miller, M.F. Greene, Max Zaritsky, Frank Duffy, A.O. Wharton, Joseph P. Ryan, Isidor B. Velasco, Matthew Woll, David Dubinsky.
- Historical File, 1934-1942 (Reel 2)
  - 001. Box 1b/Folder 2. Correspondence. September. 167 pages., 1936; 1 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Petitions and Protests regarding Suspensions, List of Protesting Unions, Resolutions, News Releases, Dual Unionism, Industrial Unionism, Committee for Industrial Organization. Principal Correspondents: George M. Harrison, David Dubinsky, A.O. Wharton, A. Phillip Randolph, Glen W. McCabe, Max Zaritsky.
  - 0168. Box 1b/Folder 3. Correspondence. October-November. 88 pages., 1936; 2 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Petitions and Protests regarding Suspensions, Dual Unionism, Committee for Industrial Organizations, Industrial Unionism, Efforts at Rapprochement. Principal Correspondents: Louis Weintraub, Max Zaritsky, Matthew Woll, George M. Harrison, Felix H. Knight, Charles P. Howard
  - 0256. Box 1b/Folder 4. Correspondence. 57 pages., 1937; 3 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: News Management, Labor Press, Committee on Industrial Organization, Efforts at Rapprochement, Union Organization (Farm Workers). Principal Correspondents: Louis Stark, Rush D. Holt, Frank Farrington, Norman Zolezzi, R.L. McCormick, John L. Lewis, Hartley W. Barclay, Fred W. Patton, Freeman Salturs, C.F. Hackman, William Hirth, Robert P. MacHatton.
  - 0313. Box 2/Folder 1. Correspondence on Industrial Unionism. 151 pages., 1935-1936; 4 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Mine Workers, Pullman Porters), Vertical Organization, Industrial Unionism, Dual Unionism, Questionnaire, Labor Press, News Management, Communist Party, National Industrial Council of the Young Women's Christian Association, Racial Discrimination. Principal Correspondents: W.B. Goll, William Collins, John M. Sherwood, Whiting Williams, George B. Roberts, Walter Nesbit, Charles W. Huff, Max D. Danish, Joseph Voorhees, Charlton Ogburn, John Brophy, Robert Riede, Len DeCaux, H.A. Bradley, Hollins N. Randolph, Joseph A. Biegel, W.C. Roberts, Jules Korchien, H. Forbes, J.F. Houchins, R. Lee Guard, George L. Googe, Rose Troiano, John F. Walker, E.F. Cronin.
  - 0464. Box 2/Folder 2. Requests for Information on Committee on Industrial Organization. 84 pages., 1935-1936; 5 (Reel 2)
    Principal Correspondents: William M. Taft, John Brophy.
  - 0548. Box 2/Folder 3. Industrial Unionism Endorsements. 62 pages., 1936; 6 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Local Unions, Central Labor Unions, Federation of Labor.
  - 0610. Box 2/Folder 4. Organization Policy Circular Letters. 75 pages., 1936; 7 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Miami Executive Council Meeting of 1936, Committee for Industrial Organization, Industrial Unionism. Principal Correspondents: J.C. Shanessy, Lewis G. Hines, W.M. Tucker, J.A. Franklin, Thomas Cairns, Roy Horn, Rowland Watson, H.A. Bradley, George L. Googe, T.A. Rickert, A.O. Wharton, Leon DeVeze, D.W. Tracy, W.J. Gillooly, John Possehl, Joseph D. Orr, William J. McSorley, E.J. Manion, Fred H. Fljozdal, J.S. Wilds.
  - 0685. Box 2/Folder 5. Industrial Unionism Speech Correspondence. 60 pages., 1936; 8 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Reactions to an Address Delivered before the United Mine Workers of America by William Green on February 3, 1936, Industrial Unionism. Principal Correspondents: Fred W. Baer, Frank Duffy, James Maloney, Morris c. Feinstone, Harry Fishwick, William J. Kelly, John J. Mara, W.J. Gillooley, Harry C. Bates.
  - 0745. Box 2/Folder 6. Press Releases on the Formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization. 53 pages., 1935-1936; 9 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Industrial Unionism, Dual Unionism, Union Organization (Committee on Industrial Organization). Principal Correspondents: John L. Lewis, Charles P. Howard.
  - 0798. Box 2/Folder 7. Press Releases on the Formation of the Committee on Industrial Organization. 56 pages., 1937; 10 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Metal Workers, Auto Workers), Tampa 1937 Annual Convention, Industrial Unionism, Dual Unionism. Principal Correspondents: John L. Lewis, Charles P. Howard, John P. Frey, Woodruff Randolph, Edward J. Volz, Louis Stark, Michael F. Greene, Jonathan Eddy, Frank Morrison, Francis Gorman, Sidney Hillman.
  - 0854. Box 2/Folder 8. statements on Industrial Unionism by John P. Frey. 45 pages., 1935-1936; 11 (Reel 2)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Metal Workers), Committee on Industrial Organization, Dual Unionism.
- Historical File, 1934-1942. Convention File, 1935-1952. (Reel 3)
  - 0001. Box 3/Folder 1. Proceedings [Indexed] of the executive Council of the American Federation of Labor, in the Matter of Charges Filed by the Metal Trades Department Against the Committee for Industrial Organization and National and International Unions, 1936; 1 (Reel 3)
  - 0345. Box 3/Folder 2. Correspondence and Papers regarding Revocation of the Charter of the Contra Costa Central Labor Council (Richmond, California), Toronto Central Trades Council (Ontario, Canada). 38 pages., 1937-1938; 2 (Reel 3)
  - 0383. Box 3/Folder 3. Correspondence and Resolutions regarding the Revocation of Charters of the National and International Unions Previously Placed under Suspension. 60 pages., 1937-1938; 3 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Miami 1938 Executive Council Meeting, Minutes of Meetings, Union Organization (Steel Workers), Revocation of Charters. Principal Correspondents: G.M. Bugniazet, John L. Lewis, Clarence E. Swick, Reid Robinson, Paul W. Fuller, Sidney Hillman, S.H. Dalrymple, Charlton Ogburn, Louis Leonard, M.F. Tighe, B. Frank Bennett, W.D. Mahon, George M. Harrison, Frank Duffy, Homer Martin, George F. Addes, A.O. Wharton, Frank Morrison, Felix Knight, Matthew Woll, T.A. Rickert, Francis Gorman.
  - 0443. Box 3/Folder 4. Relations of Local Unions with the Committee of Industrial Organizations. 75 pages., 1938-1944; 4 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Machinists, Boilermakers, Maritime Workers), Seattle and Bellingham, Washington, American Youth Congress, Labor's Nonpartisan League, Mediation, Political Mobilization. Principal Correspondents: P.W. Osburn, Joseph A. Padway, Thomas Crowe, H.W. Brown, F.D. Laudeman, I.A. Sandvigen, Charles E. Hughes, Meyer L. Lewis, Fred Kruse, Harry Nicholas, C.W. Doyle, Leo F. Flynn, F.J. Lowry, Guilford Moe, Roy Lancaster, John T. Jones, Eric Peterson, George L. Berry.
  - 0518. Box 3/Folder 5. Correspondence regarding Organizers' Applications. 108 pages., 1937; 5 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Union Organization (Mine Workers), Negro Organizers, Anthracite Settlement, Campaigns against Committee for Industrial Organizations.
  - 0626. Box 3/Folder 6. Correspondence from Organizers. 49 pages., 1941-1942; 6 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Dual Unionism, Campaigns against Committee for Industrial Organizations, National War Labor Board, Labor Journals. Principal Correspondents: J.T. Woodward, J.J. Brown, William F. Knight, George W. Taylor, William H. Davis, Cornelius Maiden, Paul J. Smith, John P. Coyne, W.D. Mahon, Felix H. Knight, Roy Horn, Sidney Hillman.
  - 0675. Box 3/Folder 7. Papers regarding United Construction Workers, CIO Organizing Committee. 20 pages., 1939; 7 (Reel 3)
  - 0695. Box 3/Folder 8. Correspondence with Congressmen and Senators regarding the Congress of Industrial Organizations. 71 pages., 1940; 8 (Reel 3)
  - 0766. Box 3/Folder 9. News releases from Harry Bridges Defense Committee. March 19-September 4. 89 pages., 1941; 9 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Congress of Industrial Organizations, Union Organization (Longshoremen and Marine Workers Industrial Union), Federal Bureau of Investigation, Gangsters, Deportation Proceedings for Alleged Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) and Communist Affiliations.
  - 0855. Box 4/Folder 1. Correspondence and Papers relating to Conventions. 153 pages., 1935-1936; 10 (Reel 3)
    Major Subjects: Atlantic City 1935 Annual Convention, Tampa 1936 Annual Convention, 1935 Executive Council Sessions, 1936 Executive Council Sessions, Committee for Industrial Organization, Industrial Unionism, dual Unionism, Suspensions, Efforts at Rapprochement. Principal Correspondents: George H. Lakey, A.O. Wharton, John Possehl, Joseph Jones, John L. Lewis, Sidney Hillman, Charles P. Howard, D.W. Tracey, John P. Frey, Max Zaritsky, Joseph Obergfell, Charlton Ogburn, David Dubinsky, Matthew Woll, Edward Flore, Walter Smethurst.
- Convention File, 1935-1952 (Reel 4)
  - 0001. Box 4/Folder 2. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 60 pages., 1937; 1 (Reel 4)
    Major Subjects: 1937 Executive Council Sessions, Industrial Unionism, Dual Unionism, Committee for Industrial Organization, General Motors Corporation Settlement, Union Organization (Auto Workers, Miners, Steel Workers), Revocations of Charters, Rules of Order on Seating Members of Committee for Industrial Organization at Convention, Progressive Miners Union of Illinois. Principal Correspondents: General Hugh S. Johnson, Alfred P. Sloan, Thomas Kennedy, John P. Frey, Frank Morrison, Frank Farrington, Charlton Ogburn, William L. Hutcheson, Duncan McDonald, Frank Duffy, Woodruff Randolph, Edward J. Volz, John H. Walker, Joseph A. Padway, Joseph Obergfell.
  - 0061. Box 4/Folder 3. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 26 pages., 1938; 2 (Reel 4)
    Major Subjects: Executive Council Meetings, Efforts at Rapprochement. Principal Correspondents: Daniel J. Tobin, William L. Hutcheson, John P. Frey, George M. Harrison.
  - 0086. Box 4/Folder 4. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 99 pages., 1939; 3 (Reel 4)
    Major Subjects: Efforts at Rapprochement, Committee to Meet with CIO, Dual Unions, Industrial Unionism, Union Organization (Carpenters, Teamsters), News Management, Executive Council Meetings, News Releases. Principal Correspondents: President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Harry Bates, Daniel Tobin, Matthew Woll, V.L. Young, Ben Tillett, J.L. Phillips, T.A. Rickert, Frank Morrison, Edward Flore, W.D. Mahon, Frank Duffy, John P. Frey, Theodore W. Noyes, Joseph Weber, A.O. Wharton, G.M. Bugniazet, George Lynch, K.A. Franklin, Patrick E. Gorman, Joseph P. Ryan, Louis Stark.
  - 0185. Box 4/Folder 5. Correspondence and Papers relating to Conventions. 138 pages., 1940-1943; 4 (Reel 4)
    Major Subjects: Efforts at Rapprochement, Committee to Meet with CIO, Resolutions, News Management, Executive Council Meetings, War Labor Board, Jurisdictional Disputes, CIO, "No Strike" Pledge. Principal Correspondents: President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Matthew Woll, Daniel J. Tobin, John L. Lewis, Phillip Murray, Arthur H. Sulzberger, George Lynch, Robert Ramspeck, Jennings Randolph, Frank Duffy, William L. Hutcheson, Joseph A. Padway, Edward Flore, G.M. Bugniazet, Harry Bates, Harvey W. Brown, William C. Birthright, William D. Mahon, David Dubinsky, George Meany, William H. Davis, Roy Horn, John P. Frey, John J. Murphy, Walter Citrine, George M. Harrison.
  - 0323. Box 4/Folder 6. Correspondence and Papers relating to Conventions. 180 pages., 1944-1948; 5 (Reel 4)
    Major Subjects: Executive Council Meetings, Political Collaborations with the Congress of Industrial Organizations, Union Organization (Building Trades and Machinists), News Management, Labor Journals, Panama Canal Zone, Legislative Issues (Taft-Hartley Act), Committee to Meet with the Congress of Industrial Organizations, Joint Statement AFL-CIO Conference, Resolutions, Workmen's Circle State Federations, Central Labor Councils, United States Supreme Court. Principal Correspondents: Phillip Murray, George M. Harrison, William E. Maloney, James O'Kane, Matthew Woll, Walter Citrine, George Meany, W.C. Hushing, W.D. Mahon, William L. Hutcheson, Harry Bates, John L. Lewis, Daniel J. Tobin, G.M. Bugniazet, N.C. Doherty, David Dubinsky, Felix H. Knight, Alan S. Haywood, Harry E. O'Reilly, K. de Jonge, Theodore Bonaventura, J. Albert Woll.
  - 0503. Box 5/Folder 1. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 177 pages., 1947; 6 (Reel 4)
  - 0504. Box 5/Folder 1. Alaska Territorial Federation of Labor. 11 pages., 1947-1948; 7 (Reel 4)
  - 0511. Box 5/Folder 1. Amendments to the American Federation of Labor Constitution. 36 pages., 1947; 8 (Reel 4)
  - 0547. Box 5/Folder 1. Automobile Safety Campaign. 4 pages., 1947; 9 (Reel 4)
  - 0551. Box 5/Folder 1. Cancer. 2 pages., 1947; 10 (Reel 4)
  - 0553. Box 5/Folder 1. Cooperative for American Relief Everywhere (C.A.R.E.). 3 pages., 1947-1948; 11 (Reel 4)
  - 0556. Box 5/Folder 1. Central and State Body Affiliates. 25 pages., 1947-1948; 12 (Reel 4)
  - 0581. Box 5/Folder 1. Civil Service Commission. 7 pages., 1947-1948; 13 (Reel 4)
  - 0588. Box 5/Folder 1. Civil Service for Firefighters. 9 pages., 1947-1948; 14 (Reel 4)
  - 0597. Box 5/Folder 1. Civil Service Status - 1st, 2nd, 3rd Class Postmasters. 3 pages., 1947; 15 (Reel 4)
  - 0600. Box 5/Folder 1. Changes of Title, International Unions. 9 pages., 1947; 16 (Reel 4)
  - 0609. Box 5/Folder 1. Communists in Government Service. 4 pages., 1947; 17 (Reel 4)
  - 0613. Box 5/Folder 1. Communism. 13 pages., 1947-1948; 18 (Reel 4)
  - 0626. Box 5/Folder 1. Communist Press. 2 pages., 1947-1948; 19 (Reel 4)
  - 0628. Box 5/Folder 1. Consumer Cooperatives and Credit Unions. 22 pages., 1947-1948; 20 (Reel 4)
  - 0650. Box 5/Folder 1. Distilling Industry, Management-Labor Conference. 3 pages., 1947-1948; 21 (Reel 4)
  - 0653. Box 5/Folder 1. Election Day Holiday. 24 pages., 1947-1948; 22 (Reel 4)
  - 0677. Box 5/Folder 1. Employment Act of 1946. 3 pages., 1947; 23 (Reel 4)
  - 0680. Box 5/Folder 2. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - Economic Mission for Europe. 26 pages., 1947-1948; 24 (Reel 4)
  - 0706. Box 5/Folder 3. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - European Recovery Plan, American Federation of Labor Represented in. 132 pages., 1948; 25 (Reel 4)
  - 0838. Box 5/Folder 4. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - European Recovery Plan, Miscellaneous. 59 pages., 1947-1948; 26 (Reel 4)
  - 0897. Box 5/Folder 5. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - European Recovery Plan, Trade Union Advisory Council. 148 pages., 1948; 27 (Reel 4)
- Convention File, 1935-1952 (Reel 5)
  - 0001. Box 5/Folder 6. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 133 pages., 1947; 1 (Reel 5)
  - 0002. Box 5/Folder 6. Extension of Social Security to Puerto Rico. 10 pages., 1947-1948; 2 (Reel 5)
  - 0012. Box 5/Folder 6. Farm Workers, Minimum Wage. 2 pages., 1947; 3 (Reel 5)
  - 0014. Box 5/Folder 6. Federal Labor Union Department Proposed. 21 pages., 1948; 4 (Reel 5)
  - 0035. Box 5/Folder 6. Fisheries, Conservation of. 10 pages., 1947; 5 (Reel 5)
  - 0045. Box 5/Folder 6. Fisheries - North American. 20 pages., 1947-1948; 6 (Reel 5)
  - 0065. Box 5/Folder 6. Foreign Labor Policy. 2 pages., 1947; 7 (Reel 5)
  - 0067. Box 5/Folder 6. Foreign Shipbuilding - American Loans. 2 pages., 1947; 8 (Reel 5)
  - 0069. Box 5/Folder 6. Fraternal Delegates - British Trades Union Congress. 65 pages., 1947; 9 (Reel 5)
  - 0134. Box 6/Folder 1. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention. 82 pages., 1947; 10 (Reel 5)
  - 0135. Box 6/Folder 1. Free Trade Union Committee Labor League for Human Rights. 12 pages., 1947-1948; 11 (Reel 5)
  - 0147. Box 6/Folder 1. Future Wage Procedure. 6 pages., 1947; 12 (Reel 5)
  - 0153. Box 6/Folder 1. Government Firing, Indiscriminate. 3 pages., 1947; 13 (Reel 5)
  - 0156. Box 6/Folder 1. Government Personnel, Abuse of. 5 pages., 1947; 14 (Reel 5)
  - 0161. Box 6/Folder 1. Hawaii. 5 pages., 1947; 15 (Reel 5)
  - 0166. Box 6/Folder 1. Hawaii, Committee to Study Conditions in. 51 pages., 1947-1948; 16 (Reel 5)
  - 0217. Box 6/Folder 1. Hollywood Jurisdictional Controversy. 9 pages., 1947-1948; 17 (Reel 5)
  - 0226. Box 6/Folder 2. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - International Labor Organization. 243 pages., 1947-1948; 18 (Reel 5)
  - 0469. Box 6/Folder 3. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - International Labor Relations Committee. 74 pages., 1947-1948; 19 (Reel 5)
  - 0543. Box 6/Folder 4. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention., 1947-1948; 20 (Reel 5)
  - 0544. Box 6/Folder 4. International Labor Relations - France. 39 pages., 1948; 21 (Reel 5)
  - 0583. Box 6/Folder 4. International Labor Relations - Germany. 68 pages., 1947-1948; 22 (Reel 5)
  - 0651. Box 6/Folder 5. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention - International and Labor Relations - Greece. 131 pages., 1947-1948; 23 (Reel 5)
  - 0783. Box 6/Folder 6. Correspondence and Papers relating to Convention., 1947-1948; 24 (Reel 5)
  - 0784. Box 6/Folder 6. International Labor Relations - Italian American Labor Council. 2 pages., 1947; 25 (Reel 5)
  - 0786. Box 6/Folder 6. International Labor Relations - Italy. 16 pages., 1948; 26 (Reel 5)
  - 0802. Box 6/Folder 6. International Labor Relations - Japan. 41 pages., 1947-1948; 27 (Reel 5)
  - 0843. Box 6/Folder 6. International Labor Relations - Jewish Labor Committee. 2 pages., 1947; 28 (Reel 5)
  - 0845. Box 6/Folder 6. International Labor Relations - Korea. 47 pages., 1947-1948; 29 (Reel 5)